<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>ILB Computing</title>
	<atom:link href="/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Your technology partner</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 03:07:23 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-AU</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Permian</title>
		<link>/packaged-offerings-permian/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[ilb_admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 01:57:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorised]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7706</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Client ILB Computing had an existing client with a long established family owned and operated self storage business The Problem Their equipment was ageing and becoming less reliable and they also required greater flexibility to efficiently manage operations from multiple locations. A industry standard management system requires a database back end so client/server bandwidth and...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/packaged-offerings-permian/">Permian</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">ILB Computing</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h4 class="p1"><b>Client</b></h4>
<p class="p2">ILB Computing had an existing client with a long established family owned and operated self storage business</p>
<h4 class="p1"><b>The Problem</b></h4>
<p class="p2">Their equipment was ageing and becoming less reliable and they also required greater flexibility to efficiently manage operations from multiple locations. A industry standard management system requires a database back end so client/server bandwidth and latency is an issue.</p>
<h4 class="p1"><b>Cloud solution</b></h4>
<p class="p2">By moving the server to AWS EC2, and all workstations to AWS Workspaces, we created a far more flexible infrastructure that allowed easy shared access between and avoided the upfront cost of purchasing new servers and workstations and associated data replication between branches or RDP licenses.</p>
<p class="p2">The server size is instantly scaleable to suit the changing needs of the business.</p>
<p class="p2">Each workspace is accessible via the “converted” old workstations. At other locations each user will have remote access to the “same” workspace so they are familiar with the workstation. With a simple VPN solution, printing to all locations is simple.</p>
<h4 class="p1"><b>Cost breakdown</b></h4>
<ul>
<li class="p2">Server Move $1386</li>
<li class="p2">Server hosting &amp; workspace cost per month $829</li>
<li class="p2">Workspace setup $2541</li>
<li class="p2">VPN setup $192.50</li>
<li class="p2">Misc configuration and setting up apps $385</li>
<li class="p2">Hardware $1461.38</li>
</ul>
<h4 class="p1"><b>Total cost and time to complete migration</b></h4>
<p class="p2">$5965.88 + $829 per month ( 6 workspaces plus cloud storage and VPN server )</p>
<p class="p2">( Note the monthly cost can be reduced significantly by prepaying for 1-3yr periods )</p>
<p class="p2">Total project time 10 days including training.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/packaged-offerings-permian/">Permian</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">ILB Computing</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>South Coast 4 Wheel Drive</title>
		<link>/packaged-offerings-sc4wd/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[ilb_admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 01:56:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorised]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7712</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Project Name 4WD service centre cloud migration Client ILB Computing had an existing client with 20 staff in 1 location. The business has been operating for 25 years servicing the local area with a vehicle servicing outlet and retail premises selling 4WD related equipment. The Problem Their server was getting old and required frequent reboots...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/packaged-offerings-sc4wd/">South Coast 4 Wheel Drive</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">ILB Computing</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h4><b>Project Name</b></h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">4WD service centre cloud migration</span></p>
<h4><b>Client</b></h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">ILB Computing had an existing client with 20 staff in 1 location. The business has been operating for 25 years servicing the local area with a vehicle servicing outlet and retail premises selling 4WD related equipment.</span></p>
<h4><b>The Problem</b></h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Their server was getting old and required frequent reboots and the disks were beginning to fail.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The computer workstations were getting old and having increased issues.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The client wanted to open a second branch to offer service in another area closer to a growing market.</span></p>
<h4><b>Cloud solution</b></h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">By moving the server to AWS EC2, and all workstations to AWS Workspaces, we created a far more robust and flexible infrastructure and avoided the upfront cost of purchasing new servers and workstations and associated data replication between branches or RDP licenses.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The server size is instantly scaleable to suit the changing needs of the business.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Each workspace is accessible via the “converted” old workstations. As the new location will share staff with the current location, each user will have remote access to the “same” workspace so they are familiar with the workstation. With a simple VPN solution, printing to either location is simple.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The only workspaces that needed to be created were the ones for concurrent staff so staff that move between locations don’t need expensive workstations.</span></p>
<h4><b>Cost breakdown</b></h4>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;">Server Move $660</span></li>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;">Server hosting &amp; workspace cost per month $589 </span></li>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;">Workspace setup $825</span></li>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;">VPN setup $220</span></li>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;">Misc configuration and setting up apps $220</span></li>
</ul>
<h4><b>Total cost and time to complete migration</b></h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">$1925 + $589 per month ( 6 workspaces plus cloud storage and VPN server ) </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">( Note the monthly cost can be reduced significantly by prepaying for 1-3yr periods )</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Total project time 3 days including training</span></p>
<h4><span style="font-weight: 400;">AWS Services used</span></h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">VPC, EC2, Route53, Workspaces, Directory services</span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/packaged-offerings-sc4wd/">South Coast 4 Wheel Drive</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">ILB Computing</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Small Business &#8211; working remotely</title>
		<link>/packaged-offerings-generic/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[ilb_admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 01:24:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorised]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7715</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Project Name AWS accelerate &#8211; Configuration of business services to allow staff to operate from home where necessary. Client A Client requires staff to have remote working capacity should the need arise. This requires moving the phone systems to VOIP and migrating computers and servers to the cloud. Once complete the staff now have the...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/packaged-offerings-generic/">Small Business &#8211; working remotely</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">ILB Computing</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h4><b>Project Name</b></h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">AWS accelerate &#8211; Configuration of business services to allow staff to operate from home where necessary.</span></p>
<h4><b>Client</b></h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A Client requires staff to have remote working capacity should the need arise. This requires moving the phone systems to VOIP and migrating computers and servers to the cloud. Once complete the staff now have the capacity to work from anywhere via Amazon workspaces.</span></p>
<p>ILB staff arrived after hours, picked up servers and took offsite ready for fast migration. Another staff member installed the workspaces client on all workstations ready for the morning of working in the cloud. The next morning, Staff could login to workspaces accessing the data that was on the server (including a SQL server based application that was migrated to an EC2 instance). They can then, after some basic training, work from anywhere with the same access to the data and systems that they had in the office. Some took their workstations home to work on and others started to use thin clients we provided.</p>
<p>Phones were moved to soft phones inside workspaces, and simple diversions on the phone line allowed immediate access to phones while working remotely. We will schedule the number ports to save the company the diversion costs shortly.</p>
<p>Future work could include moving to RDS for better fault tolerance, however the main requirement was to allow staff to work from remote locations.</p>
<h4><b>Cloud solution</b></h4>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">By moving the server to AWS EC2, and all workstations to AWS Workspaces, we create a far more robust and flexible infrastructure that can be operated from home if and when required.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The server size is instantly scaleable to suit the changing needs of the business in the current challenging environment.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Each workspace is accessible via the users current workstations so there is no outlay for new equipment. </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">With a simple VPN solution, printing to either location is simple.</span></li>
</ul>
<h4><b>Cost breakdown</b></h4>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Server Move &#8211; $1100 including setting up SQL server express on EC2 and doing a database migration. Included AD replication from old server.<br /></span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Server hosting &amp; workspace cost per month $118 per workspace approx </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">VOIP phone costs per month &#8211; $11 per extension </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Workspace setup $165 per workspace approx </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">VPN setup $220</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Misc configuration and setting up apps $220</span></li>
</ul>
<h4><b>Total time to complete migration</b></h4>
<p>3 days including training </p>
<h4><span style="font-weight: 400;">AWS Services used</span></h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">VPC, EC2, Route53, Workspaces, Directory services</span></p>
<p> </p>


<p></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/packaged-offerings-generic/">Small Business &#8211; working remotely</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">ILB Computing</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Gerringong Physiotherapy</title>
		<link>/package-offerings-gerringong-physiotherapy/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[ilb_admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 00:44:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorised]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7709</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Client ILB Computing had an existing client with a busy and growing Physiology practice over multiple locations. The Problem The servers were getting old and required frequent reboots. The computer workstations were getting old and becoming unreliable. Cloud solution By moving the server to AWS EC2, and all workstations to AWS Workspaces, we created a...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/package-offerings-gerringong-physiotherapy/">Gerringong Physiotherapy</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">ILB Computing</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h4 class="p1"><b>Client</b></h4>
<p class="p2">ILB Computing had an existing client with a busy and growing Physiology practice over multiple locations.</p>
<h4 class="p1"><b>The Problem</b></h4>
<p class="p2">The servers were getting old and required frequent reboots.</p>
<p class="p2">The computer workstations were getting old and becoming unreliable.</p>
<h4 class="p1"><b>Cloud solution</b></h4>
<p class="p2">By moving the server to AWS EC2, and all workstations to AWS Workspaces, we created a far more flexible infrastructure that allowed easy shared access between and avoided the upfront cost of purchasing new servers and workstations and associated data replication between branches or RDP licenses.</p>
<p class="p2">The server size is instantly scaleable to suit the changing needs of the business.</p>
<p class="p2">Each workspace is accessible via the “converted” old workstations. At other locations each user will have remote access to the “same” workspace so they are familiar with the workstation. With a simple VPN solution, printing to all locations is simple</p>
<h4 class="p1"><b>Cost breakdown</b></h4>
<ul>
<li class="p2">Server Move $3542</li>
<li class="p2">Server hosting &amp; workspace cost per month $1258</li>
<li class="p2">Workspace setup $1848</li>
<li class="p2">VPN setup $462</li>
<li class="p2">Misc configuration and setting up apps $308</li>
<li class="p2">Hardware $2568</li>
</ul>
<h4 class="p1"><b>Total cost and time to complete migration</b></h4>
<p class="p2">$8728 + $1258 per month ( 12 workspaces plus cloud storage and VPN server )</p>
<p class="p2">( Note the monthly cost can be reduced significantly by prepaying for 1-3yr periods )</p>
<p class="p2">Total project time 10 days including training.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/package-offerings-gerringong-physiotherapy/">Gerringong Physiotherapy</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">ILB Computing</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Cloud Migration</title>
		<link>/case-study-cloud-migration/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[ilb_admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2019 01:50:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Coding]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://impreza.us-themes.net/satisfaction-lies-in-the-effort/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The Challenge A client was hosting their main business application (Tourism booking system) with the supplier. This solution wasn’t scalable and wasn’t up to the spike load and reliability requirements the client had. The Architecture and why we chose Amazon The services consisted of a Postgres database, multiple virtual machines running various incarnations of Linux...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/case-study-cloud-migration/">Cloud Migration</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">ILB Computing</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h4>The Challenge</h4>
<p>A client was hosting their main business application (Tourism booking system) with the supplier. This solution wasn’t scalable and wasn’t up to the spike load and reliability requirements the client had.</p>
<h4>The Architecture and why we chose Amazon</h4>
<p>The services consisted of a Postgres database, multiple virtual machines running various incarnations of Linux and nginx/apache offering services from booking forms, to API interfaces.</p>
<p>Our work consisted of training the in-house developers to start to build containers for all their services to a point that they were supplying containers to our testing environment and we were then shipping those containers into the production environment as business testing allowed.</p>
<p>There were some legacy services which were difficult to put into containers as they stored client state in local files. These were put into production as single containers so that if they ever failed, the container was simpler and faster to restart than an entire VM.</p>
<p>By using ECS and ECR we managed to get all the production services apart from the database running in containers and as this allows simple cross AZ support for replication, we have had no downtime in production since the changes.</p>
<p>The database is running on Postgres Aurora with a read replica in another AZ.</p>
<p>The ECS clusters (and each service) use health checks, and cloud watch metrics to auto scale the services and cluster as required using AWS Lambda to re-balance tasks after a scaling event and now easily allows the solution to scale during peak periods.</p>
<h4>The Benefits and the Future</h4>
<p>This solution has given the client high up times, low cost and scalability during peak times without any of the complications of the previous suppliers co-location solution.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/case-study-cloud-migration/">Cloud Migration</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">ILB Computing</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Serverless Call Centre</title>
		<link>/case-study-serverless-call-centre/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[ilb_admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2019 01:32:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Coding]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://impreza.us-themes.net/this-post-looks-beautiful-even-with-long-interesting-title/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The Challenge A small client running a call-centre needed to replace a costly legacy system that was constantly requiring updates and going down on a weekly basis. They needed a fast, scalable, reliable and cheap alternative with very little ongoing maintenance costs. The Architecture and why we chose Amazon We have developed an application where...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/case-study-serverless-call-centre/">Serverless Call Centre</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">ILB Computing</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p></p>


<h4>The Challenge</h4>
<p>A small client running a call-centre needed to replace a costly legacy system that was constantly requiring updates and going down on a weekly basis. They needed a fast, scalable, reliable and cheap alternative with very little ongoing maintenance costs.</p>
<h4>The Architecture and why we chose Amazon</h4>
<p>We have developed an application where calls are taken and then messages automatically sent to clients. Amazon was chosen due to its highly scalable and available services and was achieved using all serverless architecture to drastically reduce costs and possible downtime.</p>
<p>The system takes messages, submits them to SQS for guaranteed processing and routes to either a modern cloud service for SMS and email, or a legacy PET service for messaging to pagers. Using DynamoDB. API Gateway, Lambda, SQS, SES, SNS, S3 allows us to have very low costs, high reliability and scalability. This combines to have a very low cost of ownership.</p>
<p>This application replaces the two older server based systems that required the developer to access to maintain and repair when things went wrong. Occasionally clients would miss messages and have no way to alert staff this was happening until complaints. To resolve this we implemented SQS dead-letter queues and CloudWatch monitoring to remain on top of any issues.</p>
<p>This client has moved from on premises servers, to AWS EC2 with workspaces. Using soft- phones in workspaces has allowed call-centre staff to work from anywhere. The next phase was to replace the overly complicated server software running the old paging systems.</p>
<h4>The Benefits and the Future</h4>
<p>The resulting system is fast, scalable, reliable and cheaper than its predecessor and can be run from anywhere there is an internet connection.</p>
<p>After completing the new project, and with moving phones to another platform, it’s now possible to remove workspaces and be totally browser based to run the entire call-centre.</p>
<p>Plans are also in motion to expand the services offered by utilising even more of Amazons services including replacing the server running the VOIP system that handles calls and routes them to physical phone extensions and migrating this to AWS connect for tighter integration.</p>
<p></p><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/case-study-serverless-call-centre/">Serverless Call Centre</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">ILB Computing</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Workspaces and Scalability</title>
		<link>/case-study-workspaces-scalability/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[ilb_admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2019 01:30:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Coding]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://impreza.us-themes.net/another-interesting-single-post/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The Challenge A client was rapidly acquiring other businesses and required a solution to easily scale the end user computing part of the business including file servers. The Architecture and why we chose Amazon This solution involved moving all workstations to AWS Workspaces. This allows extremely fast deployment of workstations and bringing new staff into...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/case-study-workspaces-scalability/">Workspaces and Scalability</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">ILB Computing</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h4>The Challenge</h4>
<p>A client was rapidly acquiring other businesses and required a solution to easily scale the end user computing part of the business including file servers.</p>
<h4>The Architecture and why we chose Amazon</h4>
<p>This solution involved moving all workstations to AWS Workspaces. This allows extremely fast deployment of workstations and bringing new staff into the secure environment. Previously they were waiting up to 3 weeks to have a PC build, SOE installed and having it shipped to the correct site. Now we can deploy a new PC and have the user connected in under 30 minutes.</p>
<p>The file server solution relied on AWS EFS back end, with SAMBA file servers in an EC2 Auto Scaling group that were in each AZ where the workspaces were. This allowed auto repair and re-deployment of the file servers if any failed. The file servers would auto register with the company AD servers and update Route 53 as required to have minimal downtime incase of a failure.</p>
<p>The EFS backend allowed spot instances to be used to perform backups. These were replicas to S3 in a versioned bucket on another AWS account. The source account had a “Write Only” policy so that any archives and backups couldn’t be read by any service without access to the archive account. With some simple scripting, we could then also restore folders and files to almost any point in time if a user accidently removed some required data.</p>
<h4>The Benefits and the Future</h4>
<p>By Moving to workspaces and a shared file server on EFS, we totally removed the problem of “The files server is full” or other issues that plague most businesses. With the EFS IA migration of EFS, we could also reduce cost drastically as most files are “old” and not frequently accessed.</p>
<p>The migration also allowed teams such as the marketing team, to merge at a more rapid pace into the business to share assets and work allowing the new acquisitions to be far more efficient more quickly.</p>
<p>Compliance and security are also simpler as with Workspaces, all data saved to workspaces stays inside the AWS VPC so that if a staff member loses a device, or a device in a branch is stolen, no data is compromised.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/case-study-workspaces-scalability/">Workspaces and Scalability</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">ILB Computing</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
